<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
"http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="font-combinumerals_con" xml:lang="de-de">
  <title>Schriftart für Zahlen</title>

  <shortdesc>Mit Hilfe der Schriftart <i>CombiNumerals</i> können Sie schnell
  Nummerierungen durchführen. Die Zahlen werden auf einem Kreis abgebildet
  (invers) bzw. von einem Kreis umgeben.</shortdesc>

  <prolog>
    <author type="creator">Andreas Petersell</author>

    <publisher>petersell.com</publisher>

    <critdates>
      <created date="01.12.2009"/>
    </critdates>

    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Schriftart für Zahlen</indexterm>
      </keywords>

      <prodinfo>
        <prodname>Ditalog</prodname>

        <vrmlist>
          <vrm release="25.02.2013" version="1"/>
        </vrmlist>

        <brand>5. Petersilienbuch</brand>

        <component>Ideen für Dokumentationen</component>

        <featnum/>

        <series>Tutor</series>
      </prodinfo>
    </metadata>

    <resourceid id="font-combinumerals_con"/>
  </prolog>

  <conbody>
    <section><p>Wählt man wie im Bespiel die Art <uicontrol>Solid</uicontrol>,
    werden die Zahlen invers dargestellt. Die Zahl
    <systemoutput>2</systemoutput> wird erzeugt durch den Buchstaben
    <userinput>c</userinput>. So läßt sich vom Screenshot schnell auf einen
    ebenfalls durchnummerierten Schritt der Handlungsanleitung
    referenzieren.</p><p><fig>
        <title>CombiNumerals in Photoshop</title>

        <image alt="CombiNumerals" href="font-combinumerals.gif"
               placement="break"/>
      </fig></p></section>

    <section><title>Hinweise vom Autor zum Gebrauch</title><p>Den beiden
    TTF-Dateien ist eine Readme-Datei zum Gebrauch sowie der Installation
    beigelegt. Hier die Hinweis zum Gebrauch der
    Schrift:</p><p>CombiNumerals(tm) is <indexterm>Font
    CombiNumerals</indexterm>a typeface <indexterm>Nummerierung in
    Screenshots</indexterm>for creating circled numbers,
    <indexterm>CombiNumerals</indexterm>popular for use in Web graphics,
    documentation and instructional material, maps, signs and guide books, for
    example. With CombiNumerals, you can create any number between 0 and 99.
    Here's how:</p><p>SINGLE-DIGIT NUMBERS - The numbers 0 through 9 are
    created by pressing the A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, and J keys respectively
    (you can type either lower- or uppercase).</p><p>DOUBLE-DIGIT NUMBERS -
    The numbers 00 through 99 are created by first pressing one of the number
    keys (0-9), followed by Shift-number. For example, to create the number
    67, press the 6 key followed by Shift-7. You can also create two-digit
    circled numbers with a leading zero, 07 (0, Sh-7), for
    example.</p><p>MULTIPLE WEIGHTS - CombiNumerals is available in two
    weights -- Open and Solid. The Open weight displays numbers inside hollow
    circles. The Solid weight displays white numbers inside filled circles.
    The Solid weight is the Bold version of the Open weight.</p><p>ADDITIONAL
    CHARACTERS - Several other characters besides numerals are available in
    this font. For instance, arrows, hands, pointers, and the Mac OS and
    Windows logos (including circled M and W characters) can be created. These
    characters are commonly used by people writing documentation, but are also
    used for things like maps, signs, posters, guide books, etc.</p></section>

    <section><title>Der Autor</title><p>CombiNumerals was designed and created
    by Sean Cavanaugh, the author of Digital Type Design Guide, The Page
    Designer's Guide to Working with Type, published by Hayden Books (ISBN
    1-56830-190-1). You can contact the author via e-mail
    &lt;seanc@compuserve.com&gt;.</p></section>

    <section><title>Links zum Artikel</title><p><ol>
        <li><xref format="html"
        href="http://www.maxfonts.com/fonts/c/combi-numerals.font"
        scope="external">Download der kostenlosen Version von CombiNumerals
        von www.maxfonts.com</xref></li>

        <li><xref format="html" href="http://www.mvd.com/seanc/"
        scope="external">Buch des Autors mit Schrifterweiterung</xref></li>
      </ol></p></section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
